<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: san francisco | M.C. Pantz]]></title>
  <link href="http://mcpantz.org/blog/categories/san-francisco/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mcpantz.org/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-18T14:54:55-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://mcpantz.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Paul C. Mantz]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[pcmantz@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tony Bennet is Going to Kill Me]]></title>
    <link href="http://mcpantz.org/blog/2008/05/12/tony-bennet-is-going-to-kill-me/"/>
    <updated>2008-05-12T18:41:44-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mcpantz.org/blog/2008/05/12/tony-bennet-is-going-to-kill-me</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&hellip;I left my combat boots in San Francisco.  Seriously, when I was out in Sunnyvale for work for the week.</p>

<p>To clarify, my job shipped me out to the Bay area for a week, and a couple of long weekends.  A couple coworkers of mine are spending their time off camping &amp; climbing, I decided to hit San Francisco and  stay with Christian Perry of <a href="http://www.sfbeta.com">SF Beta</a> and Room Full of People fame.  I&rsquo;ve had a fun time cavorting in the SF social scene, and met some very interesting movers and shakers in the web world.  In a twist of irony, I spent my week working down in Sunnyvale in an industry older than a PDP-11.  Hardly what is to be expected in the Web 2.0 Mecca.</p>

<p>I suppose I haven&rsquo;t&#8217; clarified exactly what I do, so I&rsquo;ll go ahead and run it down; since it&rsquo;s a lot of fun to talk about and I&rsquo;d like people to know.  For the past couple months, I&rsquo;ve been working for a startup backup software company called <a href="http://www.zmanda.com">Zmanda</a>.  We&rsquo;re currently a leader in open source backup technology, and a fair portion of our engineers work solely on open source software; myself included.  I am heading up an effort to analyze &amp; improve <a href="http://backuppc.sourceforge.net">BackupPC</a>, and potentially integrate it with our other offerings.  This has led me to some really nitty-gritty systems level concerns, which are always fun to deal with; along with a unusually clever storage engine.</p>

<p>However, I&rsquo;m talking about San Francisco, primarily.  I had a great time.  A bloody awesome time.  The city always seems to have something to do and I am there to enjoy it.  The people are awesome and welcoming, and I got to go see a lot of what the city has to offer.  My first weekend I spent clubbing and spent time with my cousin Will, who took me out to see a few bands and then off to a bar with a Depeche Mode cover band.  Some people may call that heresy, but it was a lot of fun.</p>

<p>The next weekend I got to hang out with a bunch of college friends,  and got to see such wonders like an Absinthe bar, complete with lit ice cubes and pixies fluttering about.  I also got to reconnect with a bunch of other alums that I hadn&rsquo;t met before, but were second-degree friends.</p>

<p>Either way, it&rsquo;s a really rough decision on whether to stay in Chicago, or go out to the Bay area.  We&rsquo;ll see what happens in the next few weeks.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
