<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: sleep | M.C. Pantz]]></title>
  <link href="http://mcpantz.org/blog/categories/sleep/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mcpantz.org/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-18T14:54:55-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://mcpantz.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Paul C. Mantz]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[pcmantz@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changes in Routine]]></title>
    <link href="http://mcpantz.org/blog/2009/01/22/changes-in-routine/"/>
    <updated>2009-01-22T01:39:48-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://mcpantz.org/blog/2009/01/22/changes-in-routine</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you&rsquo;ve known me for any length of time, you&rsquo;d know I hate mornings.  We&rsquo;re not talking cutesy Garfield grumpiness, we&rsquo;re talking it&rsquo;s-sharp-objects-time distaste for life.  College let me cement a lax schedule in my life, and working from home lets it continue.</p>

<p>Over Christmas break, my sleeping schedule got completely discombobulated, since I had about eleven consecutive days.  For the next week, it was difficult for me to get up before noon, and was getting worse.  Finally a couple weeks ago, a couple naps aligned my sleep schedule in such a way that I was getting up between 5 and 7 am; something I haven&rsquo;t done since my high school days.</p>

<p>So far, the major difference is how I use my time.  I usually spend the hours between midnight and 4am doing a lot of nothing.  It&rsquo;s me time, but I&rsquo;m usually surfing the internet or watching TV.  When I get up early, I eat (something I used to not do as well), relax online for a while, then get to work.  The relaxed pace of the morning has helped me concentrate on my tasks a lot better than before.  This also lets me leave my afternoons open to socialize or work on my own projects, which I&rsquo;ve been lamenting for quite a while.</p>

<p>However, it&rsquo;s harder for me to stay up late.  During the week I&rsquo;ve been going to bed at about midnight or so, but on weekends I rarely get to bed before 4am.  Yes, my social life is just that draining.  I&rsquo;m worried about flipping schedules again, but I think I&rsquo;ll be able to maintain it.</p>

<p>I did unintentionally crash from about 5pm til midnight this past Sunday after a particularly draining night and a brunch with friends that didn&rsquo;t leave me but five hours of sleep.   This is probably also a result of sleeping only about 6 hours a night; and my body wanting to play catch-up.  Either way, I&rsquo;m going to need to find a balance, what with work and play once again coming into conflict</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
