<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: yapc | M.C. Pantz]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.mcpantz.org/blog/categories/yapc/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.mcpantz.org/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-18T15:22:22-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.mcpantz.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Paul C. Mantz]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[pcmantz@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[YAPC::NA Post-Mortem]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.mcpantz.org/blog/2012/06/17/yapc-na-post-mortem/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-17T23:37:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.mcpantz.org/blog/2012/06/17/yapc-na-post-mortem</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I attended my Fourth <a href="http://yapcna.org/">YAPC::NA</a> this past week, and just
as usual, I had a blast. Conferences are valuable experiences that allow one
to step back and re-evaluate one&rsquo;s work compared to the Zeitgeist of the
community.</p>

<p>There were a lot of excellent talks this year, and even more that I didn&rsquo;t
see.  The one that left everyone&rsquo;s jaw on the floor was
<a href="twitter.com/mcholste">Martin Holste</a>&rsquo;s
<a href="http://blog.yapcna.org/post/23780340461/perl-for-big-data">Perl For Big Data</a>. There
were a lot of talks on &ldquo;big data&rdquo; but The sheer <em>audacity</em> that this project
displayed was impressive.  Holste demonstrated lightning fast search,
management-pleasing data analysis, and massive distributed throughput on some
absurd amount of real-time data. The amazing part of it all was that his team
accomplished this not by scaling up their hardware, but by using standard open
source software to its limits.</p>

<p>Another general trend that I&rsquo;m quite happy to see is that Perl hackers are
thieving magpies. Stevan Little of <a href="http://moose.perl.org/">Moose</a> fame
demonstrated <a href="https://metacpan.org/module/Web::Machine">Web::Machine</a> as a
clone of Basho&rsquo;s <a href="http://wiki.basho.com/Webmachine.html">Webmachine</a>. I am
merely looking for an excuse to use it
now. <a href="http://www.genehack.org/">Genehack</a> also unveiled
<a href="https://github.com/genehack/HiD">HiD</a>, a Jekyll clone. I was surprised that
Miyagawa, one of the first Perl hackers to be notorious for rifling the pocket
change of other language&rsquo;s libraries, did not show off any new libraries, but
did a great talk on comparing his experiences with the Python and Ruby
ecosystems he has plumbed in the past, and how to bring the good parts back to
Perl.</p>

<p>Beyond the technical, it was fun to connect and reconnect with a lot of people
I&rsquo;ve interacted with on IRC, twitter, and in past lives at past jobs. I am
definitely looking forward to going back again in the future, and I hope to
entice more folk to YAPC, both those new to Perl and those who toil in the
shadows (you know who you are!)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
