<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: blogging | M.C. Pantz]]></title>
  <link href="http://mcpantz.org/blog/categories/blogging/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mcpantz.org/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-18T14:54:55-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://mcpantz.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Paul C. Mantz]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[pcmantz@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Old Domain, New Blog Taste!]]></title>
    <link href="http://mcpantz.org/blog/2012/06/24/old-domain-new-blog-taste/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-24T00:33:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mcpantz.org/blog/2012/06/24/old-domain-new-blog-taste</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Within the next 24 hours, my <a href="http://pcmantz.github.com">GitHub Page</a> should
be accessible any- and everywhere from my preferred vanity domain,
<a href="http://mcpantz.org">mcpantz.org</a>. Right now I am having it redirect as a
top-level domain, mostly for shortened URL length.  I would love to hear of
any downsides, other than some sort of fragility in long-term resource names.</p>

<p>Also, I need to find a decent image post, as numerous of my WordPress-era
posts had embedded URLs to images that are now broken.  I&rsquo;m not too keen on
<a href="http://imgur.com/">imgur.com</a>, and the last time I used
<a href="http://imageshack.us/">ImageShack</a> was the early 00&rsquo;s.  Does anyone have some
good, modern suggestion for long-term image hosting, particularly for
hot-linking into websites?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Old Blog Content Converted]]></title>
    <link href="http://mcpantz.org/blog/2012/05/25/old-blog-content-converted/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-25T13:14:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mcpantz.org/blog/2012/05/25/old-blog-content-converted</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I converted all my old published content from <a href="http://www.mcpantz.org">mcpantz.org</a> to this new GitHub page.  Once I confirm that everything else is in place I am going to cancel the other page, and save a few bucks on hosting. In the meantime, enjoy any content that you may not have seen before.</p>

<p>If you are redirected to this page after the domain name switch; apologies for the broken link.  Please use a newer, more stable permalink that my site now provides.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The New Year]]></title>
    <link href="http://mcpantz.org/blog/2009/01/02/the-new-year/"/>
    <updated>2009-01-02T11:55:10-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://mcpantz.org/blog/2009/01/02/the-new-year</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So here we are in 2009, and in between the hangovers and days off people are considering what they&rsquo;d like to achieve this year.  I already accomplished my major goal (see last post), but there&rsquo;s still much I&rsquo;d like to do before I feel like I&rsquo;m living a completely sane and productive life:</p>

<ul>
    <li>I&#8217;d like to start working out again.  I don&#8217;t specifically mean getting pumped in the gym, but to get back into martial arts or somehow train myself  physically.  I&#8217;m not wasting away, but I want to make sure I still am in good shape.</li>
    <li>I want to be more of a polyglot, both spoken and computational.  I want to pick up Python and Haskell in the coming year, though using darcs, haskell&#8217;s community-standard revision control system, isn&#8217;t all that appealing to me.  Beyond that, I want a good excuse to start practicing my spoken languages again, as my German&#8217;s always been abysmal and my Spanish could use some polishing.  If I&#8217;m feeling particularly ambitious, I&#8217;ll pick up French; but that&#8217;s got a snowball&#8217;s chance right now.</li>
    <li>In addition to adding new languages, I&#8217;d like to expand my toolkit.  I worked as a web programmer for half a year a while back, and I&#8217;d like to re-vamp those skills in Perl so I can put things together myself, and actually work on the web projects I&#8217;ve had in mind for a while.</li>
    <li>While it&#8217;s certainly not a major issue now, I should be putting 15-20% of my take-home pay into savings.  I&#8217;ve got a couple recurring withdrawals set up to do that right now.</li>
</ul>


<p>All in all, my goals are relatively modest, but I feel like that&rsquo;s what makes them achievable.  Call me back in a year, and we&rsquo;ll see where I am.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Employment!]]></title>
    <link href="http://mcpantz.org/blog/2008/02/22/employment/"/>
    <updated>2008-02-22T20:07:17-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://mcpantz.org/blog/2008/02/22/employment</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If I haven&rsquo;t already given you an ecstatic phone call or instant message, then I should tell you that I&rsquo;ve just accepted an offer from <a href="http://www.zmanda.com">Zmanda</a> as a design engineer.  I feel really lucky with this; as I&rsquo;m going to be working in my most familiar language (Perl) to make some fairly robust code user-friendly.  I&rsquo;ll be heading up a new project to investigate adding a new open-source project to our lineup; so I&rsquo;ll be in a lot of murky waters, but it&rsquo;s going to be a lot of fun to work with, and give I&rsquo;ll have the opportunity to collaborate while being fairly autonomous.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m sure I&rsquo;ll be blogging more about the crazy things I&rsquo;m going to end up doing in Perl as a result.  Object-oriented Perl is simple yet quite bizarre, so it&rsquo;ll be an interesting experience to delve further into its depths.  I also have a couple fun ideas for some perl modules, so keep your eyes open.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I met the Author of Dr. Fun!]]></title>
    <link href="http://mcpantz.org/blog/2008/02/10/i-met-the-author-of-dr-fun/"/>
    <updated>2008-02-10T18:11:10-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://mcpantz.org/blog/2008/02/10/i-met-the-author-of-dr-fun</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So I don&rsquo;t know if any of you are familiar with <a href="http://www.ibiblio.org/Dave/">Dr. Fun</a>, but it&rsquo;s a webcomic that I&rsquo;ve been reading since i figured out what webcomics were.  At some point in my college career I realized that the author was lurking around the basement of the Regenstein, the library at the University of Chicago, but I never went to go ferret him out.</p>

<p>It turns out that he&rsquo;s directly my friend&rsquo;s <a href="http://dwarmstr.blogspot.com/">Dean</a>&rsquo;s boss, who this week gave me some old hardware they were not using.  I met Mr. Farley, who was a quiet, enthusiastic geek; pretty much exactly like I envisioned him.  he then showed me an original VT100.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
