<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: lifestyle | M.C. Pantz]]></title>
  <link href="http://mcpantz.org/blog/categories/lifestyle/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mcpantz.org/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-18T15:01:02-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://mcpantz.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Paul C. Mantz]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[pcmantz@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[End of an Era… for the Better]]></title>
    <link href="http://mcpantz.org/blog/2008/11/29/end-of-an-era-for-the-better/"/>
    <updated>2008-11-29T19:15:05-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://mcpantz.org/blog/2008/11/29/end-of-an-era-for-the-better</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I turned 18, I was staying with my aunt and uncle in Champaign, IL; soon on my way to college.  The first thing I did that night was go down to the nearest convenience store and bought a pack of black and milds.  That didn&rsquo;t quite strike my fancy, so I switched to Marlboro Reds.  Since then, I&rsquo;ve been a pretty hardcore smoker.</p>

<p>I did manage to do a really good job of cutting back for about three months in the fall of 2006, where I was only having one cigarette a day.   Smoking was primarily a social activity for me, and my coworkers at the computer lab I was working at would often cut out about noon to re-center ourselves.  However, the stress involved with the last year of college compounded with a rather intense breakup plunged my addiction deeper than it had been before, and that&rsquo;s where it&rsquo;s been since.</p>

<p>I found that smoking is more often a psychologically fulfilling activity for me, and that was reflected in my choice of tobacco.  From Black n&#8217; Milds, I switched to Marlboro Reds, to Djarum Blacks, and then to Lucky Strikes.  Cost &amp; convenience switched me to Drum rolling tobacco in the end, which I&rsquo;ve been smoking almost exclusively for the past three years or so.  My choices were often motivated by image, and I often relied on smoking as a fashion accessory as much as anything else.</p>

<p>Every time I get sick, I&rsquo;d get nagged about how my revovery period is on the order of weeks instead of days, and that i should see a doctor.  I never considered it a major issue, because I knew what to expect.  However, recently after an illness, after I had recovered, I noticed that every time I laughed, I&rsquo;d cough.  Every time.  It was violent enough to the point where i noticed myself subconsciously trying to stop laughing.</p>

<p>For someone like me who enjoys my sense of humor in life, I found this unacceptable.   So as of Sunday night, I have not had one cigarette.  I&rsquo;ve gone cold turkey.</p>

<p>Today marks the sixth day since my last smoke, and so far I&rsquo;ve resisted the temptation many times, between going out to Neo, where at any point about 20% of the patrons are outside smoking, to simply being around people who leave the main group, and missing the change to express my usual cynicism and wit in a more relaxed, one-on-one context of sharing a mood-altering substance.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve also noticed that without the sweet, sweet nicotine coursing through my body, I&rsquo;ve become quite irritable and a bit more misanthropic than is usual for me.  However, this is usual and expected, and is supposed to end after a month or so after hating everyone.  Hopefully, I can get over being an insufferable dick to everyone, and thinking that everyone is the same, and reclaim a much healthier lifestyle.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
